Let's move the mouse down.
We can see the new hair longer hair.
There are four angles, fours, etc.
Let's take a look.
There are a total of seven types of hair.
This is a new kind of hair fabric.
And then we move it up.
In addition to these, there are also two types of hair in cotton.
Plush and Terrycloth.
Let me show you.
This is plush, which is long hair.
There is also one below, which is Terrycloth, which is its towel cloth.
You can see that we stop the light on a hair.
It can see the last state of the right side of it.
In this way, we can choose different hair types according to the state of the hair.
The material is applied to the corresponding hair.
We stop the mouse on any hair.
It has this kind of preview function.
Then we press the mouse button.
We choose this angle.
Just stick it on.
On this side, you can see that the type is fur.
And then the hair type is embryo.
This is a way to add.
Another way to add is to add a new piece of fabric.
Let's click to add.
You will find that there is a fabric here.
We look down.
First of all, its fabric type is matte.
It is not a hair fabric.
So now we select a hair fabric in the property.
Add it directly.
Then go back to this type.
Let's change the type to fur only.
Render only.
You can take a look.
There is a render only in this.
It means that its hair cannot be displayed directly in 3D.
It must be displayed in the rendering window.
Including diamonds, glass, powder, lighting, etc.
It must be in the rendering window to see the effect.
Then we change it to fur.
Then press the hair type.
You can see the hair type in this.
Most of them are already in the rendering window.
There is one called Raw Edge Denim.
This is the side of the bull.
This is not in the rendering window.
And there is also a self-designed hair type below.
We choose Angra here.
Angra 2.
These are two different ways to add hair.
It's the same as adding fabric.
Let's take a look next.
This is the effect of the fabric used in the clothing.
Let's take a look at the images I rendered.
First of all, you can see that this is the hair of Moer.
The hair of Moer is actually longer.
You can see it.
But it's not that dense.
Its shape is straight.
No obvious curve shape.
You can use it directly on the bottom of the scarf.
Then the next one.
Let's take a look at this Angra 2 hair.
This Angra 2 hair.
It's actually more loose.
Its length is a little shorter than Moer.
But it's more dense.
It has an obvious curve shape.
Mainly on the sweater.
This type of Angra 2 hair is used a lot.
Let's look down again.
This is Fox's hair.
Fox's hair is longer.
And it's more dense.
It is the longest among all hair styles.
It is more suitable for jackets, headbands, and so on.
Horseshoe can also be.
It's more flexible.
Next, let's take a look at the water sculpture hair.
The water sculpture hair.
It's with Angra 2 hair.
The density of the Angra 2 hair is similar.
But it's shorter than the Angra 2 hair.
No obvious curve shape.
It's more suitable for jackets, headbands, and so on.
You can see this hair.
It's a whole downward direction.
It goes in one direction.
Let's take a look at the water sculpture hair.
The water sculpture hair is shorter.
But it's thicker.
No obvious curve shape.
It's similar to the Angra 2 hair.
It's more often used on the sweater and scarf.
Let's take a look at the back.
Let's take a look at the water sculpture hair.
The water sculpture hair is longer.
It's thicker.
For example, the inner skirt of cotton clothes.
Or the hat on the swimsuit.
The hair on it.
Or the little bear toy.
You can use the water sculpture hair.
Let's take a look at the plush.
Let's switch.
You can see the long hair.
It's very soft.
It's often used on toys and dolls.
It's often used on pillowcases.
It's more comfortable to use this hair to cover the whole body.
Let's take a look at the bun.
The bun is shorter.
But it's denser.
It can be used on the shoulder pads, jacket, and scarf.
In order to achieve a good shape.
I adjusted the length.
You can see this hair is smoother.
And it's more glowing.
Follow me.
You can see the long hair.
It's a little bit longer.
It's like a bun.
If you look at the back, you can see the long hair.
You can see the long hair.
The long hair.
It's like a bun.
It's very long.
You can see the long hair.
Next, let's take a look at Roe H. Denny, which is the side of the cow.
It's a more monotonous way of using it, and it's used on the cow.
It's shorter and denser.
Let's take a look at Terry Cloth, which is the shortest way of using the towel.
But you can also use it on the coat of arms, or on a short-sleeved shirt.
The last one is Luxe Cuddle.
It's a short-sleeved shirt, but it's denser.
Next, let's go back to the Cloth.
Let's take a look at how to adjust the hair style.
Let's go back to the Cloth interface.
Let's open a file first.
This file is a little big, so it may be relatively small.
It will take some time.
Wait a moment.
Let's take a look at the pattern effect of the fur.
To make this pattern effect, we usually make a R-shaped plate.
But the length of the plate is slightly shorter than the length of the outline of the hat.
You can see that this is the white cloth.
We can choose this fabric.
Let's take a look.
This is Fabric 3.
Fabric 3 uses this hair.
Let's find a piece of hair at the back of the hair.
Drag it directly to Fabric 3.
Let's use this Masked Belly.
Drag it directly up.
Then slide it down.
You can take a look.
In this, you can see that the back and sides of the fabric are not fur.
They are both matte.
The main reason is that the amount of hair is relatively large.
So when dyeing hair, the front part of the hair is usually only fur.
The back and sides are still ordinary hair.
This way, you can achieve the effect of hair and increase the speed.
Let's switch to the dyeing interface.
Let's take a look at his default Masked Belly.
The effect of his dyeing.
This is his dyeing effect.
接下来来一次讲解一下毛发属性的调整 Let's take a look at the adjustment of the hair attribute once again
我们先把渲染暂停一下 Let's stop the dyeing first
停止渲染 Let's take a look here
这边有一个纹理 There is a pattern here
也就是说我们可以通过纹理的方法来表现毛发 In other words, we can express the hair by the method of the pattern
你可以使用各式各样的纹理 You can use any kind of pattern
凡是应用在服装上的纹理都可以用在这里 You can use the pattern on the clothes
比如说我们这几件衣服 Let's say we find this pattern in the wardrobe
我们切换一下它的显示方法 Let's switch its display method
我们选择这个Bow纹的这个纹理 We choose this Bow pattern
直接把它拖到这个纹理这边 Drag it directly to this pattern
然后为了显示它原来没有的样子 In order to show its original appearance
我们把它颜色调成白色 We turn its color to white
这样才能显示纹理最严实的状态 This way we can show the state of the pattern
我们点击一下刷新 Let's click on refresh
这样子的话大家就能看到 This way you can see
通过纹理的方法来表现的影响 Through the method of the pattern
表现的一个面料效果 to show the material effect
表现的一个毛发效果 to show the effect of the pattern
还是比较 It's better
给你看起来还是比较好的 It's better for you to see it
那在纹理上在毛发上面呢 On the pattern
我们基本上是用不到这个发线贴图跟置换图 We basically don't use this hair line sticker and this pattern
所以我们在这里呢就不讲这个发线贴图跟置换图 So we don't talk about this hair line sticker and this pattern here
我们可以看一下这个后面 We can take a look at the back of this
我们把它数转一下滑动 Let's slide it down
我们选择这个毛发 Let's choose this pattern
这个毛发的材质啊 The material of this hair
这里包括饱和度啊红色程度啊光泽度啊光泽度提升光滑程度 Here is the saturation, the degree of redness, the degree of light, the degree of light, the degree of light improvement
以及啊大家所期待的这个毛发渐变颜色啊 And the hair color you are looking forward to
我们首先来通过一组图片 Let's start with a group of pictures
跟大家讲一下这些毛发材质的一个基本概念 Let me tell you about the basic concept of these hair materials
我们先给大家看一下这个图片啊 Let's take a look at this picture
看一下这个饱和度啊 Look at this saturation
饱和度呢就是毛发的黑色程度 The saturation is the degree of black hair
你可以看到它的质越大它的黑色越明显 The higher its value, the more obvious its black is
可以看一下第一个啊 You can see the first one
然后看一下这个红色程度 Then take a look at the degree of redness
那红色程度呢就是表现毛发的一个红色效果 The degree of redness is a red effect of hair growth
那你可以看到它质越大它的毛发也就越红 You can see that the higher its value, the redder its hair is
但是这里需要注意的是啊 But what you need to pay attention to here is that
在饱和度为0的情况下红色程度是失效的 In the case of 0 saturation, the degree of redness is lost
也就是说如果你想要设定毛发的红色程度 If you want to set the degree of redness of hair growth
饱和度一定不能为0 You can't set the degree of redness as 0
再接下来我们来看一下这个毛发的光泽度 Next, let's take a look at the brightness of this hair
光泽度提升以及光滑度 The brightness of hair growth and lightness
那大家可以看一下光泽度呢表现的是毛发的整体光泽效果 You can take a look at the brightness of hair growth
光泽度呢表现的是毛发的整体光泽效果 The overall brightness effect of hair growth
它质越大它毛发整体越亮 The higher its value, the brighter its hair overall
而光泽度提升呢表现的是对毛发的一个反光的一个区分 And the brightness of hair growth is a distinction between hair growth and hair growth
它会让反光的部分效果更加明显 It will make the backlighting part more obvious
你发现这个图一二啊 You will find that this picture one and two
你会发现光泽度提升之后啊 You will find that after the brightness is increased
值大了之后它这个反光的地方会更加明显 After the value increases, the backlighting part will become more obvious
那这个光滑程度啊就比较好理解了 Then the degree of smoothness is easier to understand
那它质越大就越光滑嘛看起来越顺 It looks smoother when it's smooth
你们再来看一下这个 Now let's take a look at this
现在我们再看一下毛发的这个渐变颜色啊 Now let's take a look at this hair color
那我们软件里面啊现在可以做三个颜色的渐变啊 In our software, you can now make three color variations
这个也是5G2的新功能 This is also a new feature of 5G2
这里包括这个中间位置啊底部位置以及颜色差值啊 Here includes the middle position, the bottom position, and the color difference
那中间位置呢表示的是第一段毛发的比例啊 The middle position represents the first stage of hair growth
我们这里是0.5就是说白色的部分是白色就是在那里啊 We are here at 0.5, which means that the white part is white
白色黄色跟蓝色就是说白色的部分是0.5 White, yellow and blue, which means that the white part is 0.5
那后面一个呢这个是这个顶部位置跟中间位置的差值代表第二段颜色的一个比例 The difference between the top position and the middle position represents the second stage of color
黄色0.5,0.8,0.6,0.3啊 The remaining one is 1-0.8, which is 0.2
那这里是最后一段蓝色的一个比例 Here is the last stage of blue
颜色差值勾充的时候你会发现它整个毛发在渐变的过程当中它是比较和谐的 When the color difference is combined, you will find that it is more harmonious in the transition of hair
看起来是比较自然的啊没有特别的突兀 It looks more natural and there is no special distortion
那如果说我们把这个颜色差值不勾你会发现它这个毛发是整体看起来是比较突兀的 That if we don't make this color difference enough, you will find that its hair is generally more prominent
渐变的比较突兀啊 In the general process, if you set the value of its top position to be larger than the middle position
你就会发现它的颜色顺序做了一个调换 You will find that its color order is made a change
本来是黄色第二现在变成蓝色第二了啊 It used to be yellow and now it's blue
所以说大家如果在已经设定好颜色顺序的情况下 So if you have set the color order well
你就要把顶部的位置的数值设的比中间位置的数值大 You have to set the value of the top position to be larger than the middle position
那接下来我们再回到软件当中 Now let's go back to the software
来具体使用一下这些毛发材质的属性 Let's use the properties of these hair products in detail
首先我们把这个颜色把这个纹理去掉 First, let's remove the texture of this color
来换一下这个颜色 Let's change the color
我们换成这个黑白色不喝补水 Let's change it to this black and white without water
让我刷新一下看一下它的效果 Let me refresh it and see how it works
我们把它的饱和度呢先调一下 Let's adjust its saturation first
比如说我们把它调成1 Let's adjust it to 1
饱和度呢就是它的黑色程度嘛 The saturation is its blackness
我们值变大 你会发现现在就变得很黑很黑 You will find that it is now very black
我们再把它这个太黑了 Let's make it too black
把它调调小一点调成0.1 Let's make it smaller and make it 0.1
等待一下刷新 Let's wait and refresh
然后再把它红色程度调到1.1 Then adjust it to 1
你会发现它并没有很红啊 You will find that it is not very red
主要是因为饱和度跟红色程度呢主要是因为饱和度跟红色程度呢 It is mainly because the saturation and the redness
它是一起决定这个饱和度调一下 It is decided to adjust the saturation together
你会发现它现在就变成了一个暗红色 You will find that it is now a dark red
那在这件衣服上我们其实用不上这个饱和度跟红色程度 We can adjust it to 0
我们用不上这个饱和度跟红色程度我们就可以把它调成0 We can adjust it to 0
然后之后上有一些白点主要是因为它的光泽程度造成的 There are some white spots on the shirt, mainly because of the brightness
你们后面再来讲一下 Let's talk about it later
先把红色程度先调成0 Let's adjust the redness to 0 first
然后我们来改一下这个光泽度 Then let's change the brightness
因为发现它本来是灰白色嘛 We found that it was originally gray and white
不然是灰黑色它现在是有点白 But now it's gray and black
我们先把它的光泽度调小一些 Let's adjust its brightness a little bit
我们把它的光泽度调成0.3 Let's adjust its brightness to 0.3
刷新一下哦 Let's refresh it
刷新一下这个实时刷新这个渲染 Let's refresh this real-time refresh
然后再把光泽度提升也调小一点 Then adjust the brightness to 0.3
因为发现它还是有一点偏白色 We found that it's still a little bit white
我们再把这个光泽程度啊 Let's adjust the brightness a little bit
再把它调的小一些哦 Let's adjust it a little bit
它三者的数值呢共同决定了这个毛发的颜色 It's the three values that determine the color of the hair
就是它的亮度 It's its brightness
把它改到0.6我们来看一下 Let's change it to 0.6
现在你会发现它明显的就 Now you will find that it's obviously
变得接近我们设定的灰黑色这个颜色 It's getting closer to the gray-black color we set
我们这里把它稍微改的快一点点啊 Let's change it a little bit here
为了品配做后面的这个毛发渐变为了好看一些 To match the back of the hair
看起来好看一些 Let's make it look better
把它的数值是到0.58 Let's set its value to 0.58
然后我们打开这个毛发渐变颜色 Then we open this hair dye color
那中间的颜色呢我就让它做白色了 Let's make the middle color white
就让它做白色 Let's make it white
然后第三个颜色我们来做成一个黄色 Then we make the third color yellow
那颜色的搭配主要是根据这个你的衣服来 The color combination is mainly based on your clothes
然后我们把它的中间的颜色 Let's make the middle color
位置呢改成0.4 The position of the middle color is changed to 0.4
也就是把黑色的对黑色的颜色比例占0.4 That is, the ratio of black to black is 0.4
然后把顶部位置改成0.3 Then the top position is changed to 0.3
那就是白色区域是0.7-0.4 That is, the area of white is 0.7-0.4
然后是说是0.7啊就是0.3 Then it's 0.7, which is 0.3
然后无上颜色的差值啊 Then the color difference is infinite
接下来我们来讲一下这个毛发形态 Next, let's talk about the hair shape
这个前两个数值比较简单啊就是长度 The first two numbers are relatively simple
那值越大的话它肯定整个毛发就越长嘛 That is, the longer the value, the longer the hair
这个长度跟厚度把它们解起来都比较简单的 The length and thickness are relatively simple
然后我们把它30改到60 Then we change it from 30 to 60
很明显就发现这个长度就长了很多 It is obvious that this length is much longer
接下来我们再来改一下它的一个厚度 Next, let's change its thickness
把它改成0.6啊 Let's change it to 0.6
那整个毛发看起来多一些 It looks a little bit more like a hair
那关于这个下面的这个弯曲度啊追度啊以及分段数啊 Regarding this below, this bend, chasing and division
我们还是通过一些图片跟大家讲解一下这个 We still use some pictures to explain to you
跟大家讲解一下它们的概念啊 Let's talk about their concepts
它们比长度厚度要稍微难理解一些 They are slightly harder to understand than length and thickness
我们看一下先把它关掉啊现在暂停掉啊 Let's take a look at it and turn it off
那先来看一下那弯曲度其实很好理解 Let's take a look at the bend
就是它的值越大你看毛发就越弯曲嘛 It's getting bigger and bigger
没有那么一根一根根根分明的感觉啊 The hair is bending more and more
然后它的你可以看一下这个图案啊跟腿就很明显 Then you can take a look at this picture and it's very obvious
那追度呢也就是它的末端跟它的底部的一个宽度的差距 That is, its end is the width of its bottom and its bottom
也就是它的追度值越大它的顶部啊就末端它越尖越细 The difference is that its chase is just as big and its top is as thin as the end
一般来说啊我们可以如果是不是那种等宽的话 Generally speaking, we can if it's not that wide
感觉度就让它保持一就可以让它看起来细一点比较细腻 Just let it look a little bit more delicate
分段数呢就代表它一根毛发上有多少段啊 Then the division number represents how many sections it has in one hair
这个值越大就是越多一般是在你的弯曲度比较大的情况下 We usually make the division number bigger when your curve is bigger
我们会把它分段数调大 That's usually the case
普通情况下的话你就让它保持大就可以了 Under normal circumstances, you just let it stay big
弯曲度很大的时候我们调一下分段数会让它自然一些 When the curve is big, we'll adjust the division number to make it more natural
我们再回到这个图楼上中我们来调一下弯曲度啊 Let's go back to this corner and adjust the curve
你们让它就是看自然一些调成0.5 0.5
现在你可以看见刚刚分明的就是 Now you can see that it's just clearly
然后归度我们这里就不调了 And then we don't adjust the curve here
我们看一下它的密度啊 Let's take a look at its density
那密度呢它的值越大就是毛发越多嘛 It's more dense, the more hair it has, the more dense it looks
看起来越密集啊分段数我们也可以不调啊 It looks more dense, and we can also not adjust the division number
那这样子的话我们到这里就是这件营服的毛领的情况啊 That way, we're here
这样就我觉得就还可以吧 If this is the case, I think it's okay
然后我们可以现在整体看一下它的渲染效果 First of all, let's take a look at its irradiation effect
首先我们来调一下它的视角 First of all, let's adjust its viewing angle
然后看一下它的双性质 And then take a look at its double growth
整体看起来还是可以的 It looks okay
然后我们停止一下渲染 And then we stop the irradiation
然后改一下它的尺寸改到A4 And then change its size to A4
那这个也是常用的尺寸啊 This is also the usual size
这样子渲染出来会比较清晰 This way, the irradiation will be clearer
大家都知道渲染其实需要花一定的时间嘛 Everyone knows that irradiation actually takes time
咱们在直播间就不等待这个渲染的时间了 We don't wait for the time of irradiation in the live broadcast
我们直接给大家看一下这个渲染 We'll show you directly
这个渲染图啊 Let's stop the irradiation first
我们先把这个渲染停止 Let's stop the irradiation first
然后看一下这个渲染图的效果 And then take a look at the effect of this irradiation
你可以看一下这个是整个的渲染图的效果 You can see that this is the effect of the entire irradiation
包括它的一个前面它的一个侧面和后面 Including its front, its side, and its back
然后我们再回到这个客户前面 And then we go back to the front of this customer
后面还有这个默认图啊重力啊卷曲不规则等等呢 There is also this default picture behind it, gravity, curly, irregular, etc.
我们再依次来讲一下它们 Let's talk about them again
那默认图呢主要是显示这个 The default picture mainly shows this
呃在同一个版面上毛发的不同的长度厚度啊以及密度 On the same version, the different lengths and thicknesses and density of the hair are painted
我们还是通过一组图片 Let me tell you about this concept first
大家可以看到这个默认图啊 You can see this default picture
这里呢有这个颜色的渐变 From white to black
你们看到啊这个右侧这个毛发的长度啊也是不一样的 You can see that the length of the hair on the right side is also different
白色的地方呢它的默认图它的黑色的地方啊它的是没有毛发 The black part of its default picture has no hair
就说
它颜色黑色也就是它的长度只乘以0了 The color black is its length only multiplied by 0
白色呢它的长度只就乘以1了 White, its length is only multiplied by 1
你就是保它原来的长度 You can see its original length
可以看到这里的颜色从白色到浅灰色 And you can see the color here from white to light gray
然后到黑色颜色逐渐递生 Then the color gradually deepens
然后呢在右侧里面表现出来就是它的毛发的长度就是逐渐递减的 And then on the right side, the length of its hair is gradually reduced
再回到这个图片当中 Let's go back to this picture
来看一下 Let's take a look
后来应用
这个默认组装 Let's download
加载一下 Let's download
加载一个新的文件 A new file
再跟大家讲一下 Let me tell you again
就是它的颜色从白色到黑色逐渐递生 Its color gradually deepens from white to black
然后它的值就逐渐减了 Then its value gradually decreases
黑色是乘以0到白色是乘以1 Black is multiplied by 0 and white is multiplied by 1
我们点击这个再来回到这个渲染界面 Let's click this and go back to this rendering interface
还是保留上一个界面 Let's keep the last interface
刷新一下 Let's refresh
这个是我们的一个床上啊 This is our bed
床上的毯子 The blanket on the bed
我们在这个文件上面应用一下它这个默认图 Let's apply this default image on this software
你看它的光泽度造成它的表面有这种白色的点点 You can see that its luminosity causes this white dot on its surface
主要是由于它的光泽度 Mainly due to its luminosity
我们先把这个渲染暂停掉 Let's stop this rendering first
我们来到这个默认图上面点开 Let's go to this default image and click on it
我们先找一个 Let's find one first
找一个图片 Find a picture
你看到这边图片啊 You see this picture
它是有这个浅灰色 然后灰色 然后到白色 It has this light gray, then gray, then white
然后再到灰色 然后到深一点 Then to gray, then deeper
然后再逐渐到黑色 And then gradually to black
它的颜色它的颜色 Its color
有一个先是逐渐变白 First, it gradually turns white
然后是逐渐变黑 Then it gradually turns black
那按照我们刚刚所说的啊 That's what we just said
就是从白色到黑色当中 From white to black
它的是值呢是慢慢的是从1慢慢成的值 Its value is slowly from 1 to 0
越来越小黑色是乘以0 It's getting smaller and smaller
那我们直接选择这张图片 Then we directly choose this picture
添加到这个默认图的长度里面 Add it to the length of this default image
点击一下刷新 Then click refresh
我们来看一下 Let's take a look
它有没有这样一个渐变效果 See if it has such a gradient effect
你会发现啊这里呢很明显 You will find that it's very obvious here
跟刚刚跟前面这个这样日亮图很明显不一样 It's very different from the previous one
它有很明显的一个层次效果 It has a very obvious symmetry effect
就是它这个长度有这样的一个层次 It has such a symmetry in its length
在这样图当中啊我们不调整它的一个厚度 So in this picture, we don't adjust its thickness
所以咱们暂停渲染 So let's temporarily
直接调到这个密度 Let's directly talk about this density
我们来增加一下这个默认图当中的密度 Let's increase the density of this default image
我们再把这张图片运上来 Let's use this picture again
再来刷新一下 Let's refresh again
你会发现这个就是一个密度 You will find that this is a density
你会发现黑色的地方啊它就没有广化了 You will find that the black area is not saturated
没有广化了 It's not saturated
直接呈现了这个毛发原有的颜色白色了 It's not saturated
那我们向上滑动一下 Let's go up and down
我们再来把这个图片作为它的纹理运上来 Let's apply this picture as its texture
再来刷新一下 Let's refresh again
现在可以看到这个层次非常明显 Now you can see that this layer is very obvious
黑色的地方就是没有毛发了 The black area is not saturated
其他地方就是比较明显 Other places are more visible
大家可以看到我们添加了纹理图进过程图之后 You can see that after adding the texture to the picture
在不规则的下面多了一个叫转换 There is one more change below the rule
这个转换就类似于咱们用这个编辑纹理工具啊 This change is similar to what we use
去调整这个纹理啊去调整这个纹理啊 to adjust this texture with the editing tool
我们可以点开看一下里面可以调整纹理的角度 We can open it and take a look inside
可以调整纹理的角度调整纹理的宽度调整纹理的宽度调整纹理的宽度 You can adjust the angle of the texture, the width of the texture, the proportion, the proportion
高度的比例都可以 We can adjust the height of the texture
我们这里直接调整一下 We can adjust it directly here
可以看一下现在我们把它改成30之后它的变了 We can see that after we change it to 30, it will change
我们再来改一下它的一个纹理的一个宽度啊 Let's change the width of the texture
给我们把它改成90了 Let's change it to 90
发现我们把这个宽度呢魔法的默认图也改了之后啊 I found that we changed the width of the texture
它整个也都变了 It's all changed
一般来说我们是为了显示着 So in general, we want to show it
所以我们要将 So we have to
如果它的默认图啊就是跟这个纹理图都没有的话 If its默认图 is not with the texture
那这个转换这里也是没有的 Then this conversion is also not here
那这里我觉得这个并不是很好看啊 I don't think this is very good-looking
我们再把它剪开一下 Let's open it again
把它设的跟最开始类似啊把它做成一个瓶子 We set it to be similar to the beginning
把它做成一个瓶子 Let's make it a bottle
我们点错点了-2 Let's make it-2
用-2吧 Let's use-2
再来创新一下 Let's refresh it
那这个就是最后的一个成像效果 This is the final result
同样的在这里给大家展示一下最后的一个渲染图的一个效果 Let me show you the final rendering effect here
可以看一下这个是添加了 The second one is added
第二个是添加了默认图 The second one is added to the default
第三个是添加了纹理图 The third one is added to the texture
看着还是不像那么回事 It still looks like something
我们再回到软件当中 Let's go back to the software
可以看到这后面还有重力-卷区-不规则-三个属性 You can see that there are three attributes of gravity, gravity, curve and irregularity at the back
我们再来讲一下这三个属性 Let's talk about these three attributes
我们再来重新加载一个文件 Let's re-upload a document
刷新一下 Let's refresh it
我们来看一下重力以及这个卷区 Let's take a look at the gravity and curve
还是通过一组图片来跟大家讲一下重力以及卷区 We will talk about gravity and curve through a group of pictures
看一下重力重力主要是有拉力 X向Y向Z向 The gravity is mainly a force from the Z axis
拉力主要是从Z轴向下的一个力 The force from the Z axis is a force from the Z axis to the top
X向是嘴皮方向上的一个力 X向是嘴皮方向上的一个力 X is a force from the mouth to the right
正直的表向右分得很像图 The Y axis is a force from the vertical direction
Y向是垂直方向受到的一个力 The Y axis is a force from the vertical direction
就是前后方受到的一个力 It is a force from the front and back
我们再看一下我们打设我们这里的默认值是10-10 Let's take a look at the default value here
来看一下这个第二个 Let's take a look at this second one
我们来看一下这个第二张图片 Let's take a look at this second picture
它的拉力X向是10 You will find that its X-axis is 10
10就是向右嘛 10 is right
那第三张呢它是 The third one is
就是向下是-10 You will find that its force is lower than the first one
你会发现它的力是比第一张图要它整个是更向下的力相对于第一张图 You will find that its force is lower than the first one
它整个是更向下的力相对于第一张图 You will find that its force is lower than the first one
然后第四张图你会发现它的X向是向左 Then the fourth picture you will find that its X-axis is to the left
然后它的Y-axis是向下向左向下 Then its Y-axis is to the left and its Y-axis is to the right and its Y-axis is to the bottom
另外一个力的合成呢就是也就是45度左下角 The combination of the forces is 45 degrees left and down
然后第五张图你会发现它的Z方向上是10 Then the fifth picture you will find that its Z-axis is 10
就是说它有一个垂直向前的一个力啊 That is to say, it has a force that is straight forward
你可以看相比第一张它这个第五张是垂直向前的 You can see that compared to the first one, the fifth one is straight forward
然后最后一张图啊它是XY都是一个是向右一个是向下 And the last picture is XY, one is to the right and the other is to the bottom
一个是向上也就是它是一个右上角啊 One is up, that is, it is a right upper corner
跟第四张图就是有形成了一个线迷的对比 With the fourth picture, there is a sharp contrast
本来呢这个毛发应该是一个向前的一个效果 Originally, this hair should be a forward effect
但由于受到这两个这个力的一个叠加作用啊 But due to the overlap of these two forces
一个是向上一个是向右嘛 One is up, the other is to the right
所以它有一个阵地向后一个毛发向后了 So it has a position backwards, the hair is backwards
再来我们再来看一下这个卷曲 Let's take a look at this curve again
那这个卷曲呢其实相对来说比较好理解 This curve is actually relatively easy to understand
那卷曲半径也就是说它的卷曲数量它的值越大 The radius of the curve is larger
它的卷曲的毛发就越多嘛 The hair of the curve is definitely more
卷曲的效果就越明显 Let's go back to this software
我们再回到这个软件当中 Let's go back to this software
我们来看一下 Let's take a look
首先看一下这个这件衣服的毛发 First look at the hair of this dress
它是根根分明的像这个针一样 It's as clear as a needle
然后我们首先来看一下这个拉力啊 Let's take a look at this pull first
调大一点 Let's take a look
它这样就没有那种根根分明的效果 It's not as clear as a needle
然后我们看一下这个S的像 Then let's take a look at this S-shape
我们把它调成E Let's adjust it to E
看一下这个左肩上的效果啊 Let's take a look at the effect on the left shoulder
它整体就有一个向右了 The whole is to the right
然后这里我们把它再调回来 We'll adjust it back here
不需要我们就要重复一下您的状态 No need to adjust it back to the previous state
然后Y像我们把它变成一个负吧 Then let's turn Y into a negative
看一下 Let's take a look
转换一下视角 Let's change the perspective
其实你现在就可以看到它的这个 You can see it today
尤其是这个底摆的部分 Especially the bottom part
比刚开始的时候向下的描画要更多一些 It's more downward than it was at the beginning
它是一个整体向下的一个局势 It's a whole downward trend
你看到肩上基本上毛都看不见有力起来的了 You can't see any strength on the shoulders
主要是因为这个Y向加了力 It's mainly because of the Y-axis
把它再改成能量的位置了 Let's change it to a negative position
这样的肌肉 Let's take a look
看一下这个Z向 Let's take a look at the Z-axis
我们也来看一下它的效果 Let's take a look at its effect
所以把它改成 So let's change it
然后我们再来切换一下它的视角来看一下 Then let's switch its perspective again
来看一下 Let's take a look
要放大一点 Let's make it a little bigger
这里大家能看到 Here you can see
很明显看到这个肩上以及这个领口的位置 It's obvious that you can see the shoulder and the neck
很明显有一个向前 It's obvious that there's a forward position
因为Z向它就是控制 Because the Z-axis is controlled by the Z-axis
你们看到它明显有一个向前 So if you look at it from the front, it's forward
往往画一根根向前 It's a little bit forward
这里的话其实我们还是不需要 We don't need it here
我们只是给大家演示一下这样的效果 We just want this effect
再把它改成0 Let's change it to 0
再把它视角切换一下 Let's switch its perspective again
我们在后面把它的卷区半径 Let's make its curve radius
改得也大一些 Let's make it bigger
把它改成10 Let's change it to 10
再看一下 Let's take a look
你们这件衣服的长度一共是35 The length of this dress is 35 in total
所以你在改卷区半径的时候 So you don't have to go too far
也不用太过分了 When you change the curve radius
比如说这个我觉得半指已经很大了 For example, I think this half-finger is already big
但10已经很大了 But 10 is already big
如果说一共30 我们改成40 If we change it to 40 in total
很明显就不合理 It's obviously unreasonable
然后我们再来把这个卷区的数量 Then let's change the number of this curve
也稍微改得大一些 A little bit bigger
比如说改成20 Let's change it to 20
卷的数量多一些 It's a little bit bigger
整体看起来就更柔和一些 It looks more gentle
下面这个不规则我们再来点开一下 Let's click on the irregularity below
先等一下这个刷新 Let's wait for this refresh
等开这个不规则 Let's wait for this irregularity
不规则其实是表现不均匀的毛发 The irregularity is actually a hair that does not perform evenly
那我们首先来看一下 Let's take a look first
等一下刷新 Let's wait for the refresh
这个试试刷新其实有点慢 This trial refresh is a little slow
首先我们将这个长度稍微改一下 First, let's change the length a little bit
比如说我们把它改成1 For example, let's change it to 1
比如说长度非常不遗孕 It means that the length is very weak
那有时有长有短 Sometimes the length is short
这样子看起来就是比较整体看起来比较和谐 It looks more harmonious in this way
然后我们把这个你先再点它渲染太慢了 Then we put this on first
它渲染太慢了 小心 It's too slow, be careful
我们先把它的厚度就可以改一下 We can change its thickness first
改成1.2 It can be changed to 1.2
然后它的方向 Then its direction
这里方向我们如果想要它同一个方向的话 If we want it in the same direction
我们就把它的方向可以改成0 We can change its direction to 0
大家就看一下这个重力 Let's take a closer look at the gravity
如果你想要去调整它不规则的这个重力 If you want to adjust the gravity of it
你首先要查看一下它这个弯曲度 You first have to check its bending
如果只有在弯曲度不为0的情况下 Only in the case of bending
你才能去调整它的一个重力 You can adjust its gravity
因为重力本来就会导致一个弯曲 Because the gravity will lead to a bend
你的弯都不弯曲了 Your bend is not bent
你要重力 You have to force it
就是没有办法去调整它的一个不规则 There is no way to adjust its irregularity
因为它是两者相矛盾的 Because it is two-dimensional
如果你是弯曲度为0的话 If your bend is 0
所以如果调整重力 So if you adjust the gravity
它的弯曲度一定是不能为0的 Its bend must be 0
你在这里把它改一下 Let's change it here
改到0.5 Let's change it to 0.5
换它两毛 Let's change it to 0.5
举去半径 Just now, it was 10
我们再把它做一个特规则的 Let's make it a special rule
把它改成1 Let's change it to 1
这样子我们最后再来刷新一下 Finally, let's refresh it
这样子就是我们毛发的基本所有属性了 This is all the properties of our hair
然后我们可以看一下它最后一个刷新效果 Then we can take a look at its final refresh effect
然后我们先暂停一下它的一个渲染 Let's wait for it to refresh
然后我们先暂停一下它的一个渲染 Then we pause its refresh
然后我们看一下最后的一个渲染效果 Let's take a look at the final refresh effect
这个就是这两个渲染前后的一个效果 This is the effect before and after the two refreshes
一边一边的让我的脚分离 One by one, my feet are separated
然后变成这样比较轴口的状态了 Then it becomes a wrinkled state
包括它的底板以及它的袖口 Then its body and its sleeves
那今天基本上这个毛发的渲染到这边讲解就结束了 That's basically the end of the hair refresh today
那后面还有一些时间 Let's take a look later
来看一下大家都有一些什么问题了 Let's see if everyone has any questions
看一下大家有什么问题 Let's see if everyone has any questions
今天晚上好像很安静 Let's be quiet tonight
让我有点尴尬 It's a little awkward for me
来看一下大家有什么问题了 Let's see if everyone has any questions
今天结束的好早了 It's so early in the morning today
等大家都没什么问题 We both have no questions
所以就可以回家睡觉了 So we can go home and sleep
我们来看一下大家有什么问题 Let's see if everyone has any questions
这个泰迪毛可以做吗 Can we make a teddy bear?
泰迪毛可以做啊 We can make a teddy bear
你可以把它 泰迪毛它不是比较卷吗 You can make it...
泰迪毛它不是比较卷吗 You can make it...
你可以把它的卷随半径调得大一点 You can make its half径调得大一点 You can make its half径调得大一点
然后长度稍微调得多一点 然后不规则调得大一点 Then the length is a little bit longer
然后不规则调得大一点 Then the irregularity is a little bit larger
这个白色毛发是说白色渲染不出毛发的效果吗 Does this white hair dye mean that white hair dye cannot produce hair dye?
如果是做白色毛发的话 大家可以看一下啊 If you are doing white hair dye, you can take a look at it
如果是做白色毛发 你们需要在这边把渲染的品质把光源调成very high If you are doing white hair dye, you need to adjust the color of the dye to very high
包括它的属性也可以调整成very high And its properties can also be adjusted to very high
羊羔绒的话是用智幻图来表示的 羊羔绒 is represented by the illusion
不是用毛发来表现的 It is not represented by hair dye
我们可以看到在库里面是有很多羊羔绒 We can see that there are a lot of sheep羔绒 in the library
在这边有这个 In here there is this
在这里啊 这里就有这个Shaper这个Fleece Poly 它这里都是羊羔绒 In here there is this shaper, this fleece poly, it is all sheep羔绒
但是呢它不是通过毛发的形式来表现的 But it is not represented by hair dye
它是通过智幻图来表现的 It is represented by智幻图
因为它并没有毛发那么细吧 Because it is not as thin as hair dye
羊羔绒还是比较像这个时候比较厚的 The sheep羔绒 is more thick
全部智幻的边缘跟以前一样 Is the edge of all the shaper the same as before?
是不是你的智幻图是不是没有做那个高色模糊 Is your shaper not made of high color blur?
流酥的效果 流酥的效果可以啊 How about the texture of the shaper?
流酥的效果的话其实是建议大家做那个纹理 The texture of the shaper is actually recommended for people to do that pattern
要么你就可以把小板片切成有这个的 Or you can cut the shaper into this one
这样用毛发来表现有这个效果 But with hair dye, it has this effect
没有板片来的逼真 Without the shaper, it will be more realistic
上面的牛仔毛须破洞怎么做 How to do the bull's fur hole on the top
牛仔毛须破洞的话是建议用贴图的方式 The bull's fur hole is recommended to use a sticker
贴图的方式的话渲染出来就是比较逼真 The sticker method is more realistic
其实在软件里面也有这个水洗的效果 In fact, there is also this water wash effect in the software
在Hardware and Trims里面有这个 In Hardware and Trims, there is this
Washing Texture
这边就有一些 There are some here
像这种就是建议大家用这个 Like this one, it is recommended that you use this
偏近格式的贴图直接贴贴进来 With the sticker pattern of the editing format directly pasted in
衣服的毛边 What kind of fur is the fur of the clothes?
衣服的毛边是哪一种毛边呢 What kind of fur is the fur of the clothes?
如果是普通的毛边的话 If it's a normal fur,
完全可以用这个用偏近格式的纹理直接添加进来就可以 You can just add it directly with the pattern of the editing format
如果是那种非常细非常细的毛边 If it's a very fine, very fine fur
就刚刚类似于刚刚牛仔布的那种毛边的话 Just like the fur of the bull's fur just now
你就可以用这个毛发里面 You can use this hair in this hair
牛仔布的毛发来做 You can use this hair in the hair of the bull's fur
就是这个毛发种类里面的 This is the hair of the bull's fur
叫做Raw-Edged Denim It's called Raw-Edged Denim
对毛发如果是比较长的话 If the hair is long,
它的那个明显的颜色确实是不容易显示 It's not easy to show the明显 color
但是如果你想要它明显非常明显的话 But if you want it to be very obvious,
你需要加一个内部线 You need to add an inner line
将内部线设定它的角度这样子的话 Set the inner line to its angle like this
然后再加明显它会明显一些 And then add the line to make it more obvious
我今天好像长得比较快 I seem to grow faster today
然后好像很多人都是踩进来的 And then it seems like a lot of people are stepping in
不好意思 I'm sorry
能不能做个渐变的灰色 Can you make a gradient gray
灰色毛球 麻灰色毛球 Gray hair ball
可以啊 If it's a gray hair ball
你可以做一个小版片嘛 You can make a small version
然后把它的渲染厚度设的大一些 And then set its rendering thickness to be larger
然后它就是一个圆圆的小圆 It's a small circle
然后你在那个圆上呢 And then you're on that circle
运用那个纹理图 灰色灰码色 And then you use the texture picture
麻灰色的纹理图 Gray hair ball gray color texture picture
然后把它设这个 And then set it
在这个用default 它这个毛画属性 And then you use default to set its texture
然后你再来看一下 Then you take a look again
我前面用这个图片看 I used this picture before
给大家解释这个毛画的一些特性 To explain some of the features of this painting
比如说它的一个弯曲性啊 For example, its curve
红色程度等等 Redness, etc.
我就是用那个毛球嘛 I'm just using that hair ball
比较大的毛 我让它是比较大的毛球 Bigger hair ball
我让它是比较大的毛球 Bigger hair ball
后面这20分钟让我很尴尬 So the last 20 minutes made me very embarrassed
所以 So
如果大家没啥问题 If you don't have any questions
咱们要不今天就45或者是50分 Let's do 45 or 50 minutes today
结束 Let's finish
毛领我讲了也 Sorry, I talked too much
不好意思 I'm sorry
我讲的有点快 I speak a little fast
我本人讲话读速就比较快 I speak fast
所以 So
我给大家直播的时候可能 When I give you a live broadcast
比莫莉老师讲的要快一些 Maybe
比莫莉老师讲的要快一些 I speak faster than Ms. Moly
下一次多向莫莉老师学习 Next time I will learn from Ms. Moly
如果是刚刚说了细毛绒的话 If it's a thin hair
你可以用那个plush来做 You can use that plush
因为plush它就是 It's similar to
类似我们一些玩偶上面的 Like some of the toys
玩偶上面的毛发 It's softer
它是比较软的 If it's a thin hair
如果是细毛绒的话 It can be used as a plush
它的毛发其实是很短的 Its hair is actually very short
3D可以 We glow can make shoes
但是 But
可能需要你多摸索 You may need to touch more
这表示今天听了一点懵逼的同学 This means that today I listened to a bit of a dreamy student
表示很抱歉表示很抱歉 I'm sorry
我讲话好快 I speak so fast
不好意思 Sorry
如果你的毛发都从扣子里面扎出来了 If your hair is pulled out of the button
像我这个其实是开衫 It's like this
它本来就有这种效果 It has this effect
如果是你的毛发不需要这种效果的话 If your hair doesn't need this effect
让扣子突出来对吧 Let the button come out, right?
你可以把扣子的厚度调大一些 You can adjust the thickness of the button
就是扭扣 It's a button
你可以选择这个扭扣 You can choose this button
然后将扭扣的一个厚度 And then the thickness of the button
就它的厚度调的大一些 Adjust its thickness a little bit
你厚度越大 You get bigger
你在正面看到它就没有 You can see it on the front
它就是毛发的扣子是在外面的 It's just that the button is outside
毛发中体现多色毛发中体现多色 Hair has many colors
我刚刚讲的是渐变色 I just talked about gradient color
灯光的调整的话 If the lighting adjustment
就可以看上一节课 You can look at the last lesson
上一节课我们有做这个灯光的讲解 In the last lesson, we have done this lighting explanation
时间比较久大家可以去看 Time is relatively long, you can go and see
帽子毛发在里层的血脉就可以跑出来 The hair on the front of the hat will run out
如果你的帽子毛发是在里层的 If your hat hair is on the front
你这里面你就只需要将后面 You just need to put it in the back
刚刚我讲的所有的毛发 Just now I talked about all the hair
我们默认的毛发里面 It's all hair in our default hair
它设定在了前面 It's all hair in the front
如果你是帽子的后 If you are the back of the hat
帽子的礼物你就把毛发设定到后面 You just put the hair in the back of the hat
然后前面是用普通的matter And then the front is a normal matter
然后你需要调节一下它的力度啊 Then you need to adjust its strength
就是它这个重力 It's about its weight
它整体向前方大概要把Z向调的大一些 It's about to make the Z side a little bit bigger
然后X向跟Y向的话尽量可以不调它 And then X and Y can be adjusted as much as possible
这样子的话就可以让它整体是向前的 In this case, you can make it whole forward
没有向左右方向的也没有向后的 And not to the left or right
就不会有这样子一个穿透 It won't have such a hole
那鞋子是可以做的 The shoes can be made
但是可能做起来虚 But it may be done
需要一些时间 You need some time
也需要去摸索 You need to touch it
今天如果没有什么问题的话 If there is no problem today
咱们就50分结束吧 Let's finish at 50 minutes
我好像创造了我们Clou直播以来最短的时长 I seem to have created the shortest time since our Clou live broadcast
你说的密度图应该是默认图里面的密度图吧 The density chart you mentioned should be the density chart in the default chart, right?
我刚刚也有讲了这个 I just talked about this
默认图里面它的密度图 In the default chart, its density chart
所有的凡是默认图它都是有 All default charts have
要么是就是从黑色到 From black to
从白色到黑色 From white to black
那如果说你的值都需要有一个渐变的话 If your value needs to be changed
那你就把颜色区分出的多一些 Then you can divide the silver into more
比如说白色浅灰色再深一点的灰色 For example, white, light gray, darker gray
然后再暗灰色然后最后到黑色 Then dark gray and finally black
你们就是有一个从白到非这样的一个渐变过程的一个默认图就可以了 You just have a default chart that changes from white to black
普通的默认图就是一个jpg图就可以 The default chart is a jpg chart
调整密度的不规则度吗 Is there any irregularity to adjust the density?
不规则是直接输入不规则是直接输入 The irregularity is directly input
这里面是没有密度的没有不规则的密度的 There is no density in it
我们只能通过现在我们只能通过这个默认图来调整它的一个 We can only adjust it through this default chart
同一个模块同一块板片上的不同的一个密度效果 From a different density effect on the same panel
刚才也讲了就是白色它是毛发的数值 The white one is the value of hair
比如说它原有的密度是乘以1的 For example, its original density is multiplied by 1
那黑色是原有的密度乘以0的 The black one is the original density multiplied by 0
如果这边是有毛发的但是你用了黑色的默认图 If there is hair on this side but you used black hair
那这边就会变成没有毛发 Then there will be no hair on this side
我刚刚有人问下一节课是什么内容 I just asked what the next lesson was about
下一节课是渲染的其他材质 The next lesson is the other materials for dyeing
你能看到我这边只是单独讲了这个Fur You can see that I just talked about this fur separately
下面还有其他的比如说Shining, Silk, Violet或者是Glass There are other things like Shining, Silk, Violet or Gloss
这些等等都是会变成默认图 These are all going to change
我们会在下一节课讲到 We will talk about it in the next lesson
大家可以期待下一节课 You can look forward to the next lesson
会讲很多很多的一个材质 We will talk about a lot of materials
那再下下一节课会讲一个模特 We will talk about a model in the next lesson
大家不是很多人都想要知道模特怎样去调他的pose啊等等 Many people want to know how to adjust his pose
我们还有两分钟时间 We still have two minutes
就结束了 That's it
幻彩布能渲染出来吗 Can the dyeing cloth be dyed?
可以啊 You can
你用这个幻彩的纹理来添加到这个毛发这边的纹理里面来渲染一下 You can use this dyeing texture to add to the texture of this hair
然后渲染一下它就是一个幻彩布嘛 And then dye it, it's a dyeing cloth
渲染白色毛发它会有一个黑点的话 If you dye the white hair, it will have a black spot
可能是因为这个噪点的原因 Maybe it's because of this spot
你可以把这个噪点值现在默认的是0.05 You can make this spot straight
现在默认的是0.05 You can make it smaller
你可以把它调得小一些 You can make it smaller
调到最小调到0.001 You can make it as small as 0.001
白色的是黑色的点是噪点 The black spot is the light spot
你可以把噪点值降的低一些 You can make the light spot a little lower
置换图会有黑色边界线 There will be a black border line in the drawing
那可能是你的置换图 That may be your drawing
你没做好 You didn't do well
默认图黑白会怎么贴 How to cut a black and white pattern
就是根据你的毛发效果 Based on the effect of your hair
你需要哪一个部分是凸起来的 Which part do you want to stick out
你就用白色 You can use white
后面紧接着如果是比如说长度的话 If the length is short
你就用稍微灰一些的 You can use a little bit of gray
再往后面的话如果是没有的话 If you don't have it
你就用完全的黑色 You can use black
它们没有一个具体的触执关系 They don't have a specific touch
只不过白色是能保持它原色的 It's just that white can keep its original color
一个长度 But black is not long
那是黑色呢是没有长的就是零嘛 But black is not long, it's zero
有人好像不会 We don't seem to have 5.3.24
我们来看一下这个5.2.334 Let's take a look at this 5.2.334
来移动一下内部线的图形是吧 Let's move the shape of the inner line, right?
你们看一下啊 Let's take a look
比如说我们来这边添加一个内部长方形 For example, let's add an inner rectangle here
我随便画一个内部长方形 Then we use this
然后我们用这个用这个调整版调整版片工具 Then we use this to adjust the version
我们选中这个选中这个内部图形选中这个内部图形选中这个内部图形选中这个内部图形
按住鼠标左键你随意移动 Press the left mouse button and move at will
如果你想要一个确定的位置的话 If you want a certain position
你可以按住shift键你可以按住shift键 You can press the shift button
它可以在一个米字形的方向上进行移动 It can be moved in a rice-shaped direction
并且你在移动的过程当中你可以单击右键 And in the process of moving, you can right-click
它会出现这样子的一个移动距离的端框出现 There will be such a range of movement
这个不知道你可不可以 I don't know if you can do this
应该能看到啊 You should be able to see it
然后你输入去试试就可以了 Then you just enter the data and try it
现在应该可以了吧 Now it should be fine
第一个多边形的第一个点 The first multidirectional first point
我们在画的时候呢 When we draw
它不是一点进行定位的 It's not a point
它这里确实有个定位 It does have a position here
但是它是通过它的外部线 But it's through its outer line
比如说它这个外边框 For example, its outer frame
或者是它这个中心点距离它这个外边框的距离 Or its center point distance
这里你可能需要计算一下 Here you may need to calculate
稍稍计算一下 It's a little bit of calculation
或者呢你就可以用这个测量工具啊 Or you can use this measurement tool
测量工具你先去测一下 You can test it first
比如说你往哪里测啊 For example, you go to the left
单击右键你先输入一个移动的距离 Press the right button
你先输入一个移动的距离 You first enter a moving distance
把它的点先定出来 And then you draw it
我看到你了 I see you
我给你演示了 I gave you a demonstration
希望你能明白 I hope you can understand
这个杨高荣的话会在下一节课 This Yang Gaolong will be in the next lesson
不好意思 Sorry
下一节课 Next lesson
这个是选材质啊 This is the material
杨高荣这边在默认的 Fabric inside Yang Gaolong
那咱们还是到9点结束好了 We're done by 9 o'clock
我们也撑到9点好吧 Thank you everyone
我们来看一下这个杨高荣啊 Let's take a look at this Yang Gaolong
我们把光标放在这个上面啊 We put the light on this
可以看到了 You can see that
这边也有明显的杨高荣 There is also an obvious Yang Gaolong here
我们选择一个啊 We choose one
按左键我们可以直接把它拖进来 Press the left button
我们可以直接把它拖进来 We can drag it in directly
那现在它就不是毛发了 Now it's not a hair
我们把这个毛发 You can see that
这里是Matter Here is Matter
然后我们来渲染一下 And then we're going to dye it
这个杨高荣 This Yang Gaolong
稍等一下啊 Wait a minute
我们把这里的视角稍微放大一些 We're going to zoom in a little bit here
可以看到这里 You can see here
那现在它就是一个杨高荣 Now it's a Yang Gaolong
可以看到吗 Can you see it?
我们再把它这个渲染关掉啊 Let's turn off the dyeing
我给大家看一下 Let me show you
这里杨高荣大家发现了吗 Did you find Yang Gaolong here?
它不是用毛发来进行做的 It's not done with hair
它还是普通的面料类型 Fabric Match It's still an ordinary fabric match
然后它这边有纹理 And then there's a pattern here
然后呢有发现贴图 And then there's a發現 sticker
主要的是这个置换图主要的是这个置换图主要的是这个置换图主要的是这个置换图主要的是这个置换图主要的是这个置换图
置换图来做这个杨高荣 To do this Yang Gaolong
这个边界如果有黑色的话 If there is a black border
你可以调整一下这个位移 You can adjust this position
把置换图这边点开 Put the置换图 here
这边有一个位移 There is a position here
移动 Move
没有声音吗 Is there no sound?
我的嗓子都很痛还没有声音 My throat is very painful and there is no sound
喝口水 Drink water
如果你的黑色很多的话 If you have a lot of black
你移动一下它这个移动的距离啊 You can move the distance of its movement
有个移动 There is a movement
置换图的作用它主要是用来做它这个纹理的一个厚度 The function of the置换图 is mainly used to make the thickness of its texture
当然知道发现贴图也是能看到纹理的一个激励感 Of course, you know that the發現切图也是能看到纹理的一个激励感 You can see the texture of the texture
但是发现贴图它只是表面的就是表面的一个激励感 But the发现贴图它只是表面的就是表面的一个激励感 But the发现贴图 is only the surface of the surface
可能造成一个视觉上的差别吧 It may cause a visual difference
它能看到这种凹凸不平的激励感 It can see this kind of凹凸不平 of the texture
但是置换图发现贴图它不能看到它的侧面的一个凹凸感 But the置换图发现贴图 it can't see its side of the texture
但是置换图可以 But the置换图 can
所以置换图通常用来做比较有厚度的一个 So this kind of paper is usually used to make a thicker one
比如说贴图的厚度啊或者像养膏绒这种啊 Like the thickness of the sticker or something like a high-heat cream
看起来比较厚的一种面料 It looks thicker
一动调大调小就需要你去设了 You need to try it out as you move it around
我也不知道你这个位置是偏的是什么样子的 I don't know what your position is like
所以你需要去试一下 So you need to try it out
咱们还有五分钟啊 Let's see, there are five minutes left
我还是这个时间差的可能是最准的的话 I'm still probably the most accurate
就恰好一个小时从八点到九点就恰好一个小时从八点到九点 Just an hour from eight to nine
有点小尴尬 It's a little awkward
置换图对置换图它是一个灰度图 The置换图 is a gray picture
它是一般是一个灰白色 It's usually a gray and white
灰白色能看到这种凹凸不平的效果 Gray and white can see the effect of this out of the screen
你可以去我们的官网上查一下这个置换图 You can go to our official website to check this out
它会教你 It will teach you
它会给你说怎么样去做一个置换图 It will tell you how to make a置换图 And
它需要在PS里面先做一个高色模糊 It needs to be done in PS first
让整个图上看起来比较自然一些 To make the whole outfit look more natural
不然的话它是有明显的棕角 Otherwise, it has an obvious corner
这样的话就是渲染出来的图片不是很好看 Then the pictures are not very good
好像一片沉寂也没有人来说话 I feel like there is no one to talk to
我又很尴尬 I'm embarrassed
今天我的毛发讲的确实是有点快 Today my hair is really fast
主要是我可能是个人习惯吧 It's mainly my personal habit
就是讲话也比较快 It's faster to talk
所以操作也比较快 So the operation is also faster
所以如果大家玩进来的同学 So if you play it in
可能要等到下一周来看回放 You may have to wait until next week to watch the replay
那希望我的就是今天的课程能帮助大家以后希望我的就是今天的课程能帮助大家以后 I hope my today's course can help you
在渲染毛发的时候在渲染毛发的时候 when you dye your hair
你找到这样子的一个我自己想要的毛发 You can find a hair like this that you want
渲染羊羔绒的最终效果和模拟效果差别很大 The final effect and simulation effect of dyeing羊羔绒 is very different
主要是因为这款图它跟这个毛发是一样的 It's mainly because this picture is the same as this hair
它也只能在渲染之后才能看见它的一个凹凸效果 It can only be seen after the training
效果所以的话你会发现三列当中它其实还是平的 So you will find that it is actually flat among the three
但是在渲染界面它就是一个比较明显的一个羊羔绒的面料 But it is a more obvious wool fabric in the training
马海毛的毛衣 The sweater of the sea lion
上面刚刚不是讲了吗 The sweater of the sea lion
马海毛可以直接用那个毛发直接用那个毛发 The sweater of the sea lion
那个毛发直接来做 The sweater of the sea lion
如果你是有不同的花样的话 If you have different patterns
你就直接把那个花样做成纹理直接贴进来就可以了 You can just make that pattern into a pattern and stick it in
大家如果后面有其他想要学习的东西 If you have other things you want to learn
可以在后台进行留言 You can leave a message in the background
为什么下周可以才有回放 Why there will be a replay next week
主要是因为我们处理视频也需要一些时间 Mainly because we also need some time to process the video
主要原因是希望大家多多去看我们的直播 The main reason is that we want everyone to watch our live stream
不然的话我感觉做直播也没有人看也没有人与我交流 Otherwise, I feel that no one is watching the live stream
也没有人与我交流就一个人在这默默的做也有点凄惨 No one is communicating with me and I'm just sitting here alone
有点凄惨 It's a bit miserable
毕战神佛也需要一些时间了 The battle of the sea lion also needs some time
咱们还有两分钟啊 We still have two minutes
今天来看的人应该大部分都是茉莉老师的粉丝是吗 Most of the people who came today are fans of Ms. Moly, right?
衬衫的面料质感你是用哪一种衬衫 What kind of shirt fabric do you use?
如果是那种就是透一点的话 If it's that kind of, if it's a little bit transparent
你可能就需要试一下透明度 You may need to try transparency
如果是普通衬衫的话就普通的做法就好了 If it's an ordinary shirt, the ordinary way is better
哎呀是我的粉丝吗 Thank you, thank you
下一次我直播的时候你再来啊 Next time when I'm live, please come again
布纹四组路鞋裁 You can adjust this with this edge
编辑文理工具 You can adjust the direction of this text
转一下 Turn it
这个必须必须是都是说我的吗 This must be always said by me
太感谢了 Thank you so much
内心有点澎湃 My heart is a little inflated
现在九点了咱们就要结束了 Now it's nine o'clock and we're going to end
那希望大家能多多关注我们close的直播 I hope you can pay more attention to our close live
下一期呢会有更精彩的这个毛发的其他除了毛发之外的其他材质没有毛发的 In the next issue, there will be more wonderful hair in addition to the hair
没有毛发了 There is no hair
大爱莫莉莫莉下一周就来见你了 Oh, Molly, Molly, I'll see you next week
说错了下下周 I said it wrong next week
不知道来不来 KFC I don't know if it's coming
好我们今天就到这边就结束了 Okay, that's it for today
谢谢大家今天的观看 Thank you for watching today
如果前面进来晚的同学呢到时候下一周我们来看一下这个回放啊 If you come in late, next week we'll take a look at this replay
拜拜 Bye bye
谢谢